Well, this is exciting. We're in cursor. We're going to do some vibe coding.
So first up, just to tell you some shortcut keys, which is good to know,
um, on, uh, to flip in and out the, the sidebar on the left,
the file system on a Mac, it's command B on a PC. It's control B.
So if you press that a couple of times, look at that.
You'll see that it's coming in and out. It also, uh,
it mentions that just here as well. And for the right hand bar over here, which
has the agent chat on a Mac, it's command option B and on a PC, it's control option B.
So let me do that a few times. There you go. You see? So that's something nice to get used
to. So that's how you can bring in and out the two different screens if they're not there
right now. Okay, that's oriented you.
Now we're going to look at this repo
and see what files we've got.
Okay, well I have news for you.
We don't have a lot of files.
In fact, we've only got one file in this repo.
It was a lot of palava for one file cloning this repo.
I could just give a new this file.
But here it is.
It is of course the file called agent.md,
which is the file that is going to be loaded in by default into the
agent's memory when we set it going. And if I click on it, we can have a look at it and it's
written in markdown, which means that it's got all the familiar markdown tags. That's a
main heading. That's a secondary heading. It's got different sections. It's got bulleted lists and numbered lists with various sections. You can also right click on the
file and say open preview. And if you do that, you see it in a sort of formatted way. And this is,
if you will, this is the way that the agent sees it because it sees Markdown and it interprets
it as actually being the headings that it is. So this is really looking at it the way the agent
will see it. Okay, and I wrote this agents.md. I didn't
generate it. I hand wrote it. I cranked it out and I'm going to take you through it right now.
So the idea of this project is to try and build a simple project management application,
something which has like a camban board, like you have an in in Jira or in Trello or products like
that. If you're not familiar with them, google it and you'll see what I mean. And so we want one of these things, it's like a sort of
note board with cards that you can move between them.
So I've got the first section, it's called business requirements of the
Canban project. We want an MVP, a minimum viable product, a prototype, if you will,
of a Canban-style project management application as a web app.
It should only have one board, it's keep it simple, always start simple,
have fixed five columns that can be renamed.
Each card will have a title and details only.
We want a drag and drop interface
to move cards between columns.
Okay, so that's not so simple,
but we need something that's gonna be cool.
You're gonna be able to add a card,
delete an existing card,
but no more functionality than that.
No archive, no search and filter, keep it simple.
The priority is a slick, professional, gorgeous
UI, very simple features and it should open with dummy data. There are other business requirements
they're laid out. The sorts of tricks to doing a good agents.md, you ought to lay things
out to be precise, you don't want to be ambiguous, you want to be very clear. They're generally
focused on the positives but I've got a couple of negatives in there, but that's okay. Generally focus on being sort of assertive and clear and do it in a way that
means that it's absolutely obvious what needs to be built.
And I know what you're thinking you're thinking, but Ed, when in real world,
when we're building big projects, they're much more complicated than this.
And I say patience, patience.
We've got three weeks together.
There'll be time to get more complicated.
We want to start with something neat.
Okay, so this is the requirements.
And by the way, you should feel free to change this.
If you want to have something different,
if you want to see what get the same as me
or similar to me, then stick with this.
But feel free to change it.
The technical details.
So I am going to try and tell how I want it to build it a bit.
I want it to be our next JS app.
I want it to use that technology. I want it to be in a
subdirectory called frontends. So there can be a subdirectory here called frontend. No persistence,
nothing being saved here. No user login or anything like that. Tell it to use popular libraries
as simple as possible, but with an elegant UI. There's, you might say, isn't that some repetition
with the previous section? There's no harm in repetition with these things,
particularly for the really important points
you want to make.
Be clear, it's fine to repeat yourself.
Okay, next up, I've got a color scheme.
These are my favorite colors that I use
for my various decks.
So I just pasted it in here.
I had it to hand.
You can change this up, use your own,
or just take it out.
Let it come up with its own color scheme.
You don't need to do this if you don't wish.
And then I got a strategy section.
Write a plan with success criteria for each phase
to be checked off, include project scaffolding,
rigorous unit testing, then execute the plan,
then carry out extensive integration testing
with playwright or similar, fixing defects.
Only completes when the MVP is finished and tested with the server running
and ready for the user.
I use many of these same kinds of things often, so this is something that's fairly boilerplate.
It's always good to lay it out this way.
Increasingly, it's less necessary to say things like this because this kind of strategy
is the kind of default strategy that most of these Agentic AIs are now following more
and more closely.
But there's no harm in putting it in here, and I found this was kind of helpful,
so I've kept it in.
And then at the end coding standards, these three are just three that I like to use.
Similar kind of thing, actually, I used to use a lot more than this.
I used to use this a lot, but it's becoming increasingly less necessary to say this,
because LLM's are starting to get the joke.
But I say, use latest versions of libraries,
idiomatic approaches, as of today.
I don't need to tell it the date I only need to hard code the date because they've
got access to that, but I just remind it to be cognizant that it needs to look at the
latest versions.
Keep it simple.
Never over-engineer.
Always simplify.
No unnecessary defensive programming.
No extra features.
Focus on simplicity. Again, it's less
necessary to say it now but I still see it frequently over-complicating and I
feel like you can't stress this too much. So I do. Be concise, keep read me's
minimal. Important no emojis ever. I like to put that in there because these
things love to make emojis and emojis are a pain and they just get in the way and maybe
you like emojis in which case you can take this out and let it get a town but I find
it thoroughly tires them and it also does actually cause some breaks sometimes with
Windows PCs. So I like to say no emojis. As I say you can add on more and feel free
to add on some of your own pet peeves to get this right. And it's something that can be a sort of living,
breathing document for you of the coding stands you like.
And we'll find out later how you can have things
like this in a more central place
where they're used for all of your projects.
Now, you might be thinking, okay, Ed,
but you just shown us this file,
but don't we have to learn how to write
these kinds of things ourselves?
And the answer is, well, yes,
but to be honest,
you can always just start with what I've got here
as a starting point, or you can just write one yourself
from scratch.
It actually honestly doesn't matter that much.
You've got to get into the habit of being very specific
and simple about what you want.
You don't need to give it technical details,
it can figure that out itself.
You don't need to give a color scheme.
You don't need to give it the strategy,
but you could just copy exactly what I've got here.
And the coding standards again,
you can start with exactly what I've got.
You could add to them.
Over during this course, we're going to be experimenting
with different kinds of standards and rules
that we will give these LLMs.
So this is something which you can experiment with.
You can also begin with something much more minimal.
Run it, see what you get,
and then delete everything that it's built
and rewrite this to be something that's more precise and accounts for where it went
wrong when it was just allowed to do whatever it wants.
That's a very effective technique working iteratively like that.
So these are all great ways to build your agents.md and yeah, honestly, you can always
just begin with what I have here and just updating the requirements to be what you want.
And now I'd like you to bring up the Cursor settings.
You can get to it from the settings menu or on a PC,
Control + Shift + J, on a Mac, Command + Shift + J.
Here it is.
Go to Agents,
Scroll down to the Auto Run section.
And this is now your choice.
If you know, if you have some sense of what you're doing,
you're familiar with the risks,
you can do this on YOLO mode.
Run everything unsan-boxed as we did for instant.
Now this is a very low risk.
The project we're about to do is low risk,
and personally, I'm happy doing this.
I know what's happening, I can kick it off,
I'll walk away, it's a risk I'm comfortable with,
but it's a personal preference. If you're not entirely sure about what's going on and what
you're signing up for, then please leave it auto run in sandbox or even ask every time.
And that way you'll see what it's doing at each step, the files it's creating, you will say approve,
and you can keep doing that. And you can keep doing that until you get more comfortable with
what's happening. And then you can move it into run everything,
sand, other sandbox to Yolo mode when you're ready.
But I'm here to take some risks.
So I'm going with that from the get go.
Okay, there we go.
It's time for us to begin.